SAMANTHA SANCHEZ

Orlando, FL • (407)-463-3188• samanthasanchez@knights.ucf.edu

SUMMARY

Disney College Program Intern at the Walt Disney World Resort. Freshly graduated computer engineering student at the University of Central Florida. Four-year experience working with software development. Two-year professional experience working with data and technical support. Fluent in English and Spanish.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE WALT DISNEY CO.

Disney College Program Intern Custodial – Pop Century Resort

2021 - Present

- Directed Guests around the hotel and provided recommendations based on their questions and interests.
- Practice safe behaviors and ensure to always put safety first.
- Perform role efficiently while projecting a positive image so Guests get the most out of their visit.
- Show courtesy and respect to Guests of all ages.

FLORIDA SOLAR ENGERGY CENTER

2019 - 2021

Data Engineer Research Assistant

- Created a data analysis report using Python with automated email alerts sent out the first day of each month.
- Worked with the data infrastructure team to map out the devices on the field and restructure the current ETL design.
- Analyzed data patterns using machine learning to determine issues/failures on the solar panel sensors.
- Reported progress to project sponsors on a weekly basis.

UCF IT 2017 - 2019

Technical Support Specialist

- Troubleshoot, maintain, and repair laptops, desktops, workstations, printers, and peripherals.
- Assisted students and faculty with administrative password resets, account lockouts and account setups.
- Resolved VPN-related issues and server application access issues.
- Sustained knowledge base articles to document solutions, processes, and procedures.

Global UCF 2016 - 2017

Student Leader

- Led groups of up to forty to students throughout orientation activities.
- Worked directly with departments and partnerships across campus.
- Assisted with move in and engaged with first year students and families.

CAMPUS INVOLVEMENT

SOCIETY OF WOMAN ENGINEERS UCF (SWE)

2020 - 2021

President/Committee Member

- Represented SWE when meeting with other student organizations and university officials.
- Maintained a current list of members, and sent out weekly newsletter email.
- Held and supervised all SWE general meetings and events.
- Submitted a report of activities and events held during the semester and the year.

ENGINEERING LEADERSHIP INNOVATION AND TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE (ELI2)

2019 - 2020

Technology Team Lead/Committee Member

- Held weekly Google Sprint workshops for over 50 students at EGS3031(Leadership in Engineering I).
- Created meeting schedules and hosted progress meetings based on team member's availability.
- Researched and pitched semester's tech team project to committee members.
- Showcased projects thought Engineers Week at UCF.

THEMED ENTRETAINMENT ASSOCIATION UCF (TEA)

2018 - 2020

Ryerson's Thrill Design Competition Team Member

- Participated on 10 different competition categories competing against 15 teams from different universities across the country.
- Presented in front of a 100+ persons audience including a 5-judge panel.
- Showcased strong communication and interpersonal skills while working on a team setting.

VOLUNTEER UCF 2017 - 2020

Knight volunteer

- Participated in the monthly cypress cleanup event.
- Assisted the Marine Discovery Center in New Smyrna Beach on shell bagging and plant collecting.
- Welcomed and served children on the autism spectrum families at the Autism of Greater Orlando's Annual Halloween Party.

TECHNOLOGY & ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Event Management Web Application - <u>Database Management Systems</u> - School Project

- Built a web application replicating an event manager website using PHP and SQL.
- Designed a ERD diagram corresponding to the application's database.
- Used SQL queries to filter out users with special access which will approve or deny event creation.

File-Server Project - Computer Communication Networks - School Project

- Programmed a file server in Linux Environment using C language.
- Stablished UDP server to send a file requested by a client and displayed transfer progress.

Asteroids Game – Personal Project

- Programmed an asteroids game in Java, implemented as a GUI application using 3 different Java classes.
- Created a sandbox in which the user can launch missiles to destroy asteroids while generating a score and triggering sounds.

OpenGL 3D Rendering - Personal Project

- Used C++ programing language to create 3D vector graphics of a 2D image.
- Applied texture, shade and depth to generate a detailed 3D render.

Launchpad LED Display – Personal Project

- Designed a circuit using a MSP430 launchpad, a breadboard, six LEDs, and 6 resistors($1k\Omega$).
- Programmed the LEDs to flash at a predetermined sequence by generating delays at different rates.

Air-Glider Model- Engineering leadership and Innovation Institute - Team Project

- Designed an air-glider on AutoCAD, engineered the design by using a 3D printer.
- Showcased project throughout Engineers Week events.

Portfolio Website – Personal Project

- Created my own portfolio website from scratch using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Utilized flexbox layout to create a responsive design across devices.
- Documented and updated code changes using Git.

CERTIFICATIONS & AWARDS

5 Keys Recognition

• Awarded with "Courtesy" and "Efficiency" keys by Pop Century Resort's manager Joanne Gotay. Nov. 2021

Amazon Educate Program

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification May. 2020

AWS Data Analytics Certification Jun. 2020

AWS Machine Learning Certification Jul. 2020 Jul. 2018

Ryerson Invitational Thrill Design Competition (RITDC). – <u>Themed Entertainment Association (TEA)</u>

3rd place Land Design.

3rd place Experience design.

SKILLS

- Programming: C++, C, Python, Java, SQL, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, R.
- Computer: AutoCAD, SolidWorks, MATLAB, Eagle, Arduino, Linux, GitHub, Jupyter notebook, MS Office.
- Language: Fluent in English and Spanish.
- Photography: 5-year experience on Portrait, Landscape and commercial photography.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering President's List May 2021 Minor in Mathematics Dean's List May 2021